The alias "Yst Dawson" begins to take shape in the real world

Day 00055: Friday, 2015 May 01

I had a bizarre dream in which I was riding my bike (I don't currently have a bike in the real world) with my coworker, Jon. We got to the area that my house (which was actually my former house in the real world) should have been, but my house wasn't quite right. We continued to the end of the street to check the street signs, but I found that instead of being at the corner of H and 21st, we were at the intersection of two named streets I had never heard of. During the entire ride, I had been ignoring my coworker, pretending what he said was drown out by my headphones, which I was in fact wearing, but they were turned off. Once I knew I was totally lost, I took off the headphones and quit pretending to listen to music. We talked, and it turned out we both knew this was a dream. I thought he was a figment of my dream, but he thought we were both real people sharing a dream. As I knew him from the real world, I considered the possibility, but still thought he was probably not the real Jon. At some point, I woke up, but just into another dream. In this one, there were several people that I don't know in the real world, but I did know in the dream and was convinced that I knew in the real world. By this point, I was convinced that either I was sleepwalking but experiencing the world as if I was not or that this was in fact a shared dream. If the latter, I would be able to communicate with other dreamers and convey things they didn't know in the real world only for them to confirm they got the message once we met up in the real world. These people were convinced that I was not asleep and that this was not a dream, but I told them all I needed them to do was remember a word for me. Originally, I asked the trio to remember a word that they had said. I forget the exact word now as my dream fades from my mind, but it meant something like "crazy". At the last minute, I switched to a word they shouldn't know at all: "Yst". I said the word, then spelled it for them. It's a made-up word, and there's not really a reason to know it normally. The woman in the group told me three letters: "mih". As I woke myself up, I realized I should have instead given them my email address. Once I was fully awake though, I realized that these people were fictional and not people I knew in the real world, so it didn't matter anyway.

I looked up "mih". I thought she had been speaking in text talk and that it was an abbreviation for something, but MiH is a brand of womens' jeans. Noctis of #flora said it could also be "him" backwards or an alternate spelling of "meh".

Josh Woodward released another of his song demos to his Patreon supporters yesterday. I can't say much right now due to Josh's desire to keep it mostly-secret until the full release, but it's a beautiful song and I will be ecstatic to be able to add it to my play list once it is made publicly available.

I have just ordered a credit card for Yst Dawson, an alias I've been using in the real world for a while now. This card is attached to a Discover account under my legal name, and Discover didn't ask for any personally-identifying information beyond a first and last name for the new card. The intent with their system is to add cards for friends and family members to use to spend off your account with, but it also provides a great way to avoid giving your legal name to online merchants. Discover will still have your legal name, but it's more reasonable for your money account provider to require your legal name than for a merchant to do such. Discover said the card will arrive in the mail in five to seven business days when I requested it, but I later got an email saying that I should contact them immediately if the card does not arrive in four to six business days. Once it arrives, I will likely set up my Patreon account to use the new card. Discover did not allow arbitrary characters in the add-on card holder's name, so I wasn't able to create a card suitable for making publicly-attributed payments with, as I would want them attributed to this site's Web address.

If I manage to get ahold of a tablet IMEI though, my new card should be useful for setting up service with MetroPCS. The government and criminals alike can monitor your mobile traffic. My data connection is behind Tor, so that information is safe, but they can still read account details used to connect to the mobile network with. I'm not sure if criminals can use this information but the government is able to take this information to the carriers and ask who you are. They use this information to basically take roll sometimes, often at protests and other completely-legal events that they just don't approve of. It's better that your carrier not know who you are. Of course, if the government is really trying to figure out who I am, the billing address narrows it down quite a bit. Still, it's better than using my legal name. The government should have to put a little effort into finding me if they aren't going to get a warrant first.

While on the Discover website, I tried once again to update my user name and password, but again, to no avail. I will likely try reaching out to their Web support team when I get a chance. Web support seems unavailable at this time, likely due to being after business hours.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Beginning plans for a Floraverse character

Day 00056: Saturday, 2015 May 02

I found a contact form on Discover's website, so I have now asked about the inability to change my password and user name. I downplayed the importance of changing the user name, claiming that my main concern was the inability to update the password, as I change my password frequently for security reasons. However, changing the user name is actually of greater interest to me. The user name is a reference to a domain name I lost when my hard drive died, so I want to update my user name to reflect the domain name I use now. I do want to change my password though, to a longer one than is currently set, which should be more secure.

I spent some time today considering the next steps in setting up my alias, Yst Dawson. It might be useful to update every reference to my legal name on this site to instead use my new alias, and perhaps try to scrub away my legal name from the Web a bit, such as ask Josh Woodward if he will remove my legal name from his links to this site, as I never told him what my name was and theoretically, that attribution should instead be to "y.st.", as that is my name on Patreon. I could additionally modify my whois information to reflect my alias instead of my legal name. However, I came to a chain of conclusions. First, IANA or ICANN or whoever says that domains are owned by the person whose legal name is contained in the whois database. The main implication of this is that with whois privacy, you don't actually own your domain, your whois privacy provider does. That means I should not use whois privacy, as I don't own my own domain in that case. However, by the same token, if I have the domain registered under my alias, I don't actually own the domain any more, and in case of complications, I'm pretty much powerless to prove I should be the owner. Obviously, the only good option is to use my legal name in the whois records. If someone knows where my site is, they know what my domain name is, and can look me up in the whois records. Therefor, changing my name on my site is not particularly helpful. Anywhere where my domain is mentioned, such as in a link to this place, likewise provides two ways to get my legal name: visiting the site and performing a whois search on the domain name itself. There is therefor no benefit in asking Josh to continue linking to this place but to remove my legal name. I have come to the conclusion that aside from trying to make myself harder to search for by my legal name, there is no point in redacting my legal name anywhere in which my URI or domain are mentioned publicly. Anyone who will not mention my URI publicly need not be told who I am. I will continue using my card under my legal name for Josh's Patreon campaign, but if I end up needing to use a card to pay my carrier, I will do so using my alias' card.

I tried setting my Patreon profile location to this site's URI, but Patreon wouldn't let me. Likewise, I tried mentioning this place's URI in the profile description, but Patreon censored it. However, Patreon has a glitch that gave me an idea. Every time I go to the "edit profile" page, Patreon fills in the "YouTube URI" field with my email address. If I forget to remove it and set it back to an empty string, Patreon complains that I need to begin my URI with http:// (yes, Patreon forgets that YouTube uses HTTPS instead of HTTP in this error message). If Patreon wants the user to enter the full URI and not just the user name, does that mean it will accept arbitrary Web URIs? The answer to that is "yes". Whenever I try to register a Google account, Google demands a telephone number from me, and I don't have one. Setting up a YouTube profile requires a Google account with Google+ enabled, and as I cannot get a Google account and I cannot agree to Google+'s terms of service because they demand use of a legal name for no good reason, I cannot at any point sign up for YouTube. Likewise, Facebook demands use of a legal name in their terms of service too, so I cannot register for a Facebook account. Patreon allows setting both of these profile links to arbitrary URIs, so I set the YouTube one to https://y.st/ and the Facebook URI to https://y.st/weblog/2015/.

After reading more of Floraverse, I have come to the conclusion that the first character I want to make will likely be a bonsai treant, a type of Owel treant. Owel treants are a peaceful species of tree mimics that clean the forest of dead debris. The bonsai variant is sterile, unable to produce offspring, which fits me well as an asexual in the real world. I'm not technically sterile, but I do choose to avoid breeding. Instead of breeding, bonsai treants tend to gather and plant seeds from plants they personally favor.

Speaking of the Floraverse, it seems the race that was erased in the prologue was not really erased at all. They were more ... merged. They have become amorphous blobs that seem to contain what had been the personalities of multiple previous people. They now seem to seek to assimilate others, the thought of which is quite scary. The being that originally tried to wipe them out now seems to have been split into two main parts, unable to recombine. It is unknown how much of the being's old personality still exists, but there does appear to be some left.

We need to keep pressuring Congress not to approve the Trans-Pacific Partnership. Please send a letter to your congressmen!

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My Discover account is finally up-to-date

Day 00057: Sunday, 2015 May 03

Discover wrote back, claiming that my "out-of-date" browser is the cause of the inability to change my user name and password. However, the server is throwing an error upon submission of the form, not the browser. The only reason the browser's version would have anything to do with it is if the website is doing something stupid such as sniffing the user-agent string. I'm using a fork of a fairly recent version of Firefox, as I'm using Iceweasel from the testing version of Debian. I don't have the option to upgrade unless I install the nonfree nonforked Firefox. I won't do that, and I'm convinced this isn't the issue anyway. I modified my user-agent string to claim to be the latest version of Firefox, then tried again. As expected, the form still returns an error message upon submission. The representative at Discover said that if updating the browser did not work, I should call telephone support. Dealing with telephone support, even responsive telephone support that does not put you on hold for hours, is aggravating. Thankfully, I no longer have a telephone line and cannot submit to requests that I call telephone representatives. I reported back that the browser upgrade did not work and that I have no telephone with which to call their support line. The representative told me that I should pretend my password is lost and perform a password reset. Doing so required me to dig out my Social Security card to enter the number into the site, which was annoying, but it fixed the password issue. I later went back wondering if it would have fixed the user name form, and it had. For whatever reason, changing my password made it once again possible to change my user name (and presumably my password, but I didn't check) normally. I will have to keep this in mind for next time if it happens again, though I honestly hope I never need to change my user name again. My user name is almost always tied to my domain name, so the only reason I would need to change my user name is if I ended up changing domains again. I'd really rather keep this domain if at all possible, unless I somehow manage to get an even shorter one. The only feasible way to get a shorter domain would be to apply for control of a three-character gTLD, but that is prohibitively expensive. Even shorter would be if I could control a ccTLD, but that practically would require running my own country, or a one-character gTLD, but ICANN or IANA or whoever said applications for those would only be considered for use for the public good or something like that. I forget the details, and I don't disagree with that stance, but the point is that //y.st. is the shortest name a normal guy like me is likely to manage to acquire. I've got a pretty sweet name here, and I hope never to need to change it.

I messed around with the MetroPCS site's device activation page, but it does not like either of my devices' IMEIs. Activating service on my Replicant device over the Web with MetroPCS will not be possible, even if I would settle for one of their smartphone plans instead of a tablet plan. But the fact is that MetroPCS's best smartphone plan is not as good as the secret $30 USD T-Mobile plan that T-Mobile doesn't like to tell people about. MetroPCS's plan costs the same price, comes with less high-speed data, and is on a carrier that charges $3 USD just to pay your bill (so the T-Mobile option ends up being slightly less expensive anyway). When the time comes, I'll try to get the T-Mobile tablet plan. If that doesn't work out, there's no reason why I would go to MetroPCS for a smartphone plan.

Android IMSI-Catcher Detector received an update through F-Droid today, and no longer crashes. Admittedly, after being locked out of Github for so long, I kind of gave up on trying to report that bug. I still planned to do it eventually, but I had lost my desire to get it done right away. It seems it's already been found and fixed though.

Patreon said that my payment did not go through for some odd reason. They recommended updating my payment information in case it was incorrect, which I did, but I don't know when they will try again to pay Josh Woodward with my money. I'd rather they do it sooner than later.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Continued contemplation about mobile plans

Day 00058: Monday, 2015 May 04

I found that T-Mobile's online activation process is different between "tablets" and "telephones". I figured that because the process is different, perhaps using the process they don't expect you to use on a given device might allow you to get the plan they don't expect you to have on said device. As an experiment, I tried using the tablet activation process on my old T-Mobile SIM card. The old SIM seems to have been killed remotely by T-Mobile when I left them though, so it didn't work. I next tried using my new T-Mobile SIM card that I bought when I initially wanted to switch identities but had no plans to leave them yet. I ended up leaving them before activating the card, so it's still unused. However, the tablet Web activation won't work with it. I have to conclude that either that SIM card is set up to use the regular non-tablet activation method only or that the tablet Web activation system checks to see if your device is known to be a tablet or not.

One thing I considered doing is getting an actual usable tablet and bringing it to MetroPCS for a SIM card. If I did that, I would not be paying MetroPCS for a tablet I won't even be able to use, but also not trying to trick MetroPCS into thinking I was getting a plan for what they call a "tablet" while really getting a plan for what they consider to be a "telephone". It seems the only viable options are a couple devices both informally known as the Samsung Galaxy Tab 2, as they are the only "tablets" that support Replicant. Tablets are a bit bulky, so I decided to look into the smaller of the two, the Samsung GT-P3100. However, even being an older model, it still costs about $500 USD! It might be possible to stomach that price if I didn't already have a perfectly good GT-I9300, but it's a bit steep of a price just to humor the carriers. If I get the MetroPCS plan, it will have to be with the cheapish tablet they offer. It's $150 USD, and once I have the SIM card activated, I'll never use the thing again outside of dealing with tech support, but the amount I save on monthly bills will add up. For the first ten months, I'll be in the hole, but after that, my bill is cut in half, hopefully permanently, with no down sides. I even get to give up voice service!

If I get the MetroPCS tablet, the SIM card will be too big. From what I've read, the Pop 7 that they offer takes a mini SIM card, while my GT-I9300 takes a micro. I'll need to get a SIM cutter. That won't be too expensive, but it does lead to issues if this doesn't go as planned. If I buy the tablet and cut the SIM, what do I do if MetroPCS blocks my GT-I9300 from using the tablet plan? In theory, swapping the SIM card should swap the plan, but sometimes carriers do something hokey and prevent SIM cards from working on multiple devices. As far as I know, only TracFone participates in this ridiculous, over-controlling practice, but if they can do it, so can anyone else. Until I know for a fact that MetroPCS doesn't do this, buying the tablet is a gamble. If I cut the SIM card and it doesn't work in my real mobile, how do I explain it to MetroPCS? Yeah, uh, I need to get a new SIM card. I'll pay for it, but yeah, I sort of tried bypassing your restrictive policy by moving the SIM card to my preferred device, but it needed a smaller SIM. So I cut it. But it didn't work, so I need the full mini SIM so the plan will work on the tablet that I lied to you and said I would use in the first place. I don't think that would go over well.

Why would I need the plan if it won't even work on a decent device? Why would I need to replace this cut SIM card? Basically, it boils down to the unlock policy. After having put all this money into getting the tablet, not getting it unlocked would be throwing that money away. If I at least spend a little more money to keep it in service long enough to get it unlocked, the tablet will be useful for getting other carriers to sell me data-only plans. I can't do that if the tablet is locked. MetroPCS says they will unlock a device if it has been on the network for three continuous months. Or rather, they say they will unlock "telephones" that have been on the network that long. I don't know for sure that this same policy applies to "tablets". I will have to ask when I go in tomorrow.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Another trip to a MetroPCS store because MetroPCS lacks an email/Web support option

Day 00059: Tuesday, 2015 May 05

I walked into the MetroPCS shop again to inquire further about their tablet plan so I can attempt to get it. I asked about bringing in a tablet, claiming that I was interested in the Galaxy Tab 2. It's true that that would be my preferred tablet, but it's too pricey for me at the moment. If they accept outside tablets though, there's a shot of convincing them that I want to buy a SIM for a tablet that I supposedly have at home. However, it seems that I misunderstood MetroPCS's offer. Their tablet plan is *exclusive* to the new tablet they carry. If you want their tablet plan, there is quite literally only one supported device. Though highly disappointing, this segued nicely into the topic of if the Pop 7 they are up-selling doesn't work out for my use case. I asked if I could take it back for a refund in the first couple days if it did not work well for my use case. The representative told me that as long as I brought it back in like-new condition within seven days with less than a minute of talk used, they would refund my money. She said that the talk time requirement was meaningless due to the tablet plan not having any voice service included, but that it was still technically a requirement. I explained that I don't like being locked to a particular carrier, and asked it their "telephone" unlock policy also applies to their tablet, and she assured me that it applies to every device they sell, including the tablet.

I mentioned the MetroPCS site being screwy, disallowing activations within our ZIP code, and she agreed that the site has that issue at the moment, but claims it will be fixed soon enough. She also attempted to reassure me that MetroPCS does in fact get service in the area, despite what the website says. I already knew that though, as MetroPCS is just a second face of T-Mobile these days. T-Mobile gets great service in the area, or at least they did when I last used their service. That's not really the issue. The issue is this: if the in-store representative required photo ID when the time comes for me to get my plan, I won't be able to get the plan under an assumed name. That means I will need to use the Web activation method or not get a MetroPCS plan at all in that case. Hopefully, I won't need ID in-store, but if I do, I want a second option.

I did some searching to see if MetroPCS locks SIM cards to a single device the way TracFone does, but the results were inconclusive. Some people said MetroPCS SIM can be swapped into new devices, but other people said that they cannot. I really have no idea if the SIM card from MetroPCS's Pop 7 tablet will be capable of being used in my GT-I9300. I think I still have over a month before I have to decide if I will take the risk though.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Chocolate & Cocaine

Day 00060: Wednesday, 2015 May 06

As I said yesterday, I think I have over a month left to decide if I should get the MetroPCS plan. However, at this point, I'm fairly certain I am getting it. The main deciding factor is probably my mother. She has been preasuring me to get SMS messaging back on my device, and if I choose the T-Mobile tablet plan, I won't have SMS messaging. Personally, I hate SMS messaging. However, strait up email uses up her limited data plan and due to a Verizon bug, the Verizon SMS gateway doesn't play nicely with her iPhone. As much as I would love to tell her she needs to either switch to a better carrier, or switch to a better device, or just deal with the bug, I don't need to be going out of my way to lose her favor. If I can stay on her good side, it would probably be best.

There are other reasons to go with the MetroPCS plan though. If MetroPCS keeps this plan available longer than two and a half years (an explanation of why that time frame is important is below), I'll feel pretty dumb paying for more expensive service. Even if the plan is not available for registration at that point, existing plans may still continue to function at that price. It would be nice to have such an inexpensive plan indefinitely. Furthermore, it will be an adventure. If this goes well, I get a quick victory. Not much to write about, but it will be nice. If it doesn't go well, I potentially get a lot of weblog fuel as I haggle with them. I'll also learn whether MetroPCS locks their SIM cards or not. While it will be too late for me to make a decision based on the knowledge I gain from already having made the decision, it may prove useful to someone else.

There are down sides to consider in regards to getting the MetroPCS plan as well. I recrunched the numbers, and as I said before, if the alternative to the MetroPCS tablet plan is a smartphone plan, the tablet will pay for itself in ten months. After that, my bill will be cut in half. However, if it is instead possible to get onto the T-Mobile tablet plan using my "non-tablet" device, I only save five dollars per month instead of fifteen by choosing the MetroPCS plan. At that point, the tablet pays for itself instead in two and a half years, after which I save five dollars per month. There's potentially a lot less gain than I originally implied. Furthermore, this tablet won't even be useful to me as an actual device, as it is incapable of running Replicant. Basically, all use of the tablet will revolve around using its serial number to do things. In essence, I'll be paying $150 USD for a serial number and nothing more. That seems a bit steep. Lastly, the MetroPCS plan comes with SMS messaging. This is a definite down side. I don't want to be reachable by SMS, as SMS is an incredibly inferior way to communicate. I don't like it. It is aggravating not being able to use an actual keyboard when I'm at home. By email, I can use a keyboard if I have it and a tiny touch screen if I don't. By SMS, I'm stuck with the tiny touch screen no matter what.

I updated ownCloud today, mostly following the instructions made available in the manual. However, I didn't think anything would go wrong, so I didn't back up the ownCloud server's data before starting. Apparently I have not yet learned my lesson about data loss. After the update, all the ownCloud "applications" were missing from the interface! I feared their absence meant the data stored by these applications was lost. There isn't any data that I really use in the default setup, so that would mean all meaningful data had been erased from the server (I still would have it on the client though, so I could hurry and get it back before it was lost for good). However, re-enabling the ownCloud modules made the data visible again, showing it was not lost.

The payment to Josh Woodward through Patreon went through finally, so I can rest easy about that. Speaking of music, it's was about time for me to buy another album, which I've gotten in the habit of doing about twice each month. I stopped by Lorenzo's Music's website hoping to score a copy of Bazar, but on their homepage, I saw a link to a new song they have called Chocolate & Cocaine. Both the paid and gratis download options are provided through CASH Music, a service I was unfamiliar with. Fearing CASH Music only provides MP3 files and not wanting to pay for MP3 files (I much prefer Vorbis and FLAC files), I chose the gratis download option, planning to go back and pay for it if a reasonable music format was provided. Indeed, the file was available in MP3 format only. With few exceptions, I refuse to buy MP3 files because the format is proprietary. Besides, Vorbis files have higher sound quality than MP3 files while still having a smaller file size. It's a beautiful song, and I recommend hearing it, but I went back to plan A: buy Bazar from Bandcamp. It appears that Chocolate & Cocaine is still in the demo phase, so when it is finished, it will likely be made available on Bandcamp with Vorbis and FLAC files available.

PayPal was being a pain again, refusing to allow me to make the purchase without a PayPal account. The problem is that PayPal tries to detect what country you are in and tries to prevent users in some countries from making purchases without an account. After several Tor resets and attempts to initiate the transaction, I was finally presented with the accountless transaction page.

My guess is that PayPal has faced greater resistance to their insistence that users create an account from citizens of some countries than others. In countries with greater resistance, PayPal probably provides the account-free option to avoid losing as much money, but in countries with less resistance, PayPal probably tries to get more users to create an account by not allowing them to avoid doing so. My resistance to creating a PayPal account is their own fault though. When I had an account, I had to argue with support for two months because they refused to allow me to make a single purchase and refused to delete my account, remove my credit card information from my account, or make an accountless purchase with a card tied to an account. During this period, PayPal kept demanding that I give them unfettered access to my bank account (which my credit union advised *against* doing, on the grounds that PayPals demand made them seem hokey) and copies of my Social Security card, photo ID, bank statements, credit card statements, and a utility bill in my name. I provided the photo ID, Social Security card (I know, I shouldn't have done that),and credit card statement. I explained that I'm not the one paying for utilities here, so there does not exist a utility bill in my name and that they could not have my bank account statements because my bank account was not relevant to my payments, as I was paying by credit card. I figured that there was enough information on my bank statement for them to glean the information they needed to get the unfettered access they wanted to my account, so I was not going to risk that. Though they said they unlocked my account, every time I logged in or tried to use the account, it would still be locked and PayPal was once again demanding all the things it demanded before. After several iterations, they finally agreed to close the account, but I was never able to make a purchase with it. The account was quite useless to me and cause a lot of grief. Without an account though, purchases usually go smoothly, and when they don't, I can try back later, and they eventually go through. Having a PayPal account is not a viable option for me.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Limited edition yellow vinyl

Day 00061: Thursday, 2015 May 07

I just got word that Marc with a C has released his album This World Is Scary As Fuck on yellow vinyl for a limited time. Normally, I wouldn't care too much. Vinyl is a legacy format, and it's kind of bulky, as is the player for it, so you can't listen to it wherever you like. However, this record comes with some bonus tracks (also included in digital formats when you buy the physical record) and two digital-only albums. Marc says that on June sixteenth, he will entirely delete the two bonus albums. That seems a bit destructive to me, but it does mean that now is the time to get those albums if ever.

Marc says that within 24 hours of making the purchase, he will send "codes to download" these two albums. I really hope that these are Bandcamp downloads, as then Vorbis and FLAC files will be available. Even more importantly, that would mean the albums would likely be marked as being under Marc's usual license. If the downloads end up being nonfree or in a nonfree format, I'll have already spent the money and there will be not much I can do. If the format is nonfree, I might leave well enough alone, to be honest. Or I might not. But if the tracks themselves are nonfree, I might pester Marc with a C about it. In that case, he'd likely give me an informal "yeah, those are under CC BY like the rest of my stuff", which will be fine. I honestly don't think he's trying to withhold the right to reuse, I just don't like having to put money in based on trust and not knowing for sure that the return won't be locked-down. Marc seems like a good guy though, so I'll put my $20 USD in and get the record.

... or at least I would do that, if PayPal wasn't declining my credit card again. PayPal is such a pain in the rear, I have no idea why everyone puts up with this. Please, if you are a merchant, allow your customers to pay using some non-PayPal method! By the time PayPal quit declining the card, Discover had started rejecting the transaction, likely due to how many times it had been attempted by then. I have written to Discover about the issue, and hopefully it will be solved by tomorrow. Discover's automated message said a real person would get back to me in twenty-four hours; unlike PayPal's support, Discover's support usually gets the job done.

I've been missing Twidere, as its tabs make it possible to be more efficient on Twitter than the regular Twitter interface. Tinfoil for Twitter was fixed a while ago, so now it responds in real time, but in the end, it's still just a gateway to Twitter's mobile Web interface. As you may or may not recall, I had to remove Twidere because it was crashing every time I opened the application. It didn't do that before a specific update, so hoping that an even newer update fixed the issue, I installed it again. It works again! Ive been following a lot of people lately, many of which I have no intense interest in. I want to sometimes see what my crowd is saying, but certain users more often have something valuable to say, and that valuable content gets buried amongst tons of fluff from other accounts. I'm guilty of posting fluff as well; I'm not trying to point any fingers. It is, however, nice to have a way to have a more direct way to see (some of) the gems.

I didn't get a couple messages from my boss due to them being caught by Zoho's spam filter. I waited over three hours for responses from my boss that actually arrived very quickly. This isn't the first time good mail has been sent to spam, and I tend to go through my spam box manually anyway. The only difference is that I have to check the spam box manually, but the regular inbox alerts me to new messages through my mobile's mail client, K-9 Mail. Doing some Web searching for a way to disable the spam filter, I found indications that a way to disable it was on the verge of being released two years ago, but there is no indication that it ever did get released and I can't find the option in the control panel. I did, however, stumble upon a post by a Zoho user about how to set up a custom mail filter that effectively undoes the sorting by the spam filter, though the spam filter still probably goes through the effort of sorting the mail first. In any case, there is a workaround.

Yst Dawson's credit card arrived in the mail today! However, much to my surprise, all the important numbers on it are identical to that of the card under my legal name. The only real difference is that the new card is under my alias. Does that mean that the name on the billing address does not matter; that I could supply any name I want when making an online purchase? I have no idea. Even if so, the new card could come in handy when dealing with MetroPCS in person. They may want to put me on autorenew right away to avoid their stupid $3 USD fee for paying your bill, and having the card ready will make that possible. For the record though, anything I buy on Bandcamp, including Marc's new album, links back to my Bandcamp profile. My bandcamp profile links back to my website, and therefor my domain. For that reason, I used my legal name when attempting to make the purchase, so it was not me refusing to use my legal name that prevented PayPal from taking my card. That is a separate issue.

With the new card in hand, I purchased both a SIM card cutter and a new protective case for my mobile. My current case has taken much abuse, abuse that the mobile would have taken if not for the case. The new case both protective against impacts and water, where the old one only protected against impacts. The estimated delivery date for the SIM cutter is somewhere from June third to June nineteenth. It may not arrive by the time I was planning to get the MetroPCS plan. The case will arrive sooner, estimated delivery will occur from May thirteenth to May eighteenth. I don't plan to switch cases until the MetroPCS tablet is unlocked, so the two items will arrive in the opposite of the order that would be most convenient. No worries though, I will try to be patient.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A new markup validator

Day 00062: Friday, 2015 May 08

I decided that it was a good idea to remove my legal name from my website after all. As such, I have redacted my name from all my pages (I think). If you need to know who I am, I'm still easily findable by performing a whois query on my domain name. However, I don't want to show up in search results for my legal name. I enjoy the freedom of speech I have here, and if I have to constantly worry about prospective future employers seeing what I write and refusing to hire me based on my opinions, I'll have to censor myself. I don't want to do that. I've already on at least one occasion censored myself because of this, and on at least one other occasion, I tried to justify my opinion when it didn't really call for justification. I'm done with that. There are a number of factors that will aid me in keeping my online and offline lives separate. For starters, my mother gave me a very common name. It's a nice name, but even better, so many other people share it, both first and last. Any search for my legal name turns up so many results that realistically, I don't even *need* to redact my name from this place. Second, the registry of my own country's ccTLD refuses to allow registration of short names. By driving me away to seek a home elsewhere on the Internet, somewhere associated with another country, Neustar made it less likely that search engines will consider my website to be relevant to searchers in my country. This has negative implications as well, such as the fact that I won't turn up in results for things I *do* want to be found for by people of my country, but it helps me evade those that I would need to censor myself from. My currently-self-signed TLS certificate might drop me in search rankings as well.

Mistedwind forward a letter from Mike of the W3C. In regards to the fact that the W3C validator refuses to connect, Mike recommends instead using a different validator on the site. This one actually works! It throws errors about things that are not actually errors (It doesn't like the <acronym/> tag), so I needed to clean a few things up, but I have now updated the link atthe bottom of each page to use the new validator. It also throws a warning about is skipping over my DTD declaration. I'm not sure what to do about that, I can't just leave out the DTD declaration and expect the page to still be valid.

As a side note, if you notice day 14 missing from the weblog, it's because of issues with PHP's highlight_string() function. As mentioned before, this function spits out a mess, including heavy use of the &nbsp; entity and the style <span/> attribute. I had been going to create a new function to fix this, but had deemed it too much effort to complete. The new validator is calling me out on use of &nbsp; though, so I'm going to have to at least fix that. And if I am building a function, I need to build it to actually work, so I'm going to have to fix the use of the style attribute as well. I don't have time for this today though, so I took the page down to avoid invalidity.

I have so much email to catch up on. Perhaps tomorrow I will go through it and post relevant links here. It looks like things are going on politically, but I haven't had the time these past few days to pay attention to it.

At the time of writing this, Discover has not yet gotten back to me, but it's worth noting that I had to get this entry written up and uploaded before noon. I'll be at work most of the day, and won't have time to write this later.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Discover doesn't seem to understand that because I do not have telephone service, I cannot call their stupid number

Day 00063: Saturday, 2015 May 09

Discover wrote back while I was at work. They told me that to get the issue with the card cleared up, I need to call some support number. Keep in mind that this message from Discover was in response to a letter by me in which I explicitly said that I lack a telephone and cannot call support. I can only assume that the representative either totally spaced it; not realizing that if I lacked a telephone yesterday, I probably lack a telephone today too; only skimmed my letter, saw their department couldn't help, and redirected me to telephone support without getting to the part about me not being able to call; or something else of that nature. I responded stating, once again, that I do not have a telephone and cannot call this support number. This time, I kept my message short and did not mention anything besides being unable to call that number because I lack a telephone. If they read my letter at all, they won't be under the impression that I can call their other department.

Cricket sent me an SMS message yesterday stating that my bill is coming due, as if it wasn't past due already. For those who don't remember, I'm letting my Cricket line die. As it's prepaid, you simply cancel it by not paying. Cricket has cut off my ability to make and receive calls, as they should have, but has left my account in an odd limbo state where I am not paying but still have a data connection. I expect this to end in about a month, when I will likely be cut of entirely.

I looked into getting a prepaid debit card, but it appears that the USA PATRIOT act prevents someone from getting one anonymously. This is sheer idiocy. For a line of credit, sure, it makes sense to require a way to track you down if you don't pay up. But on something that is prepaid, they don't need to know who you are. I'm not trying to hide from my card issuer, but the problem with giving them information about who you are is that they will put your legal name on the card. There are certain businesses that want me to pay by card that I do not want knowing who I am (read: MetroPCS). If Discover refuses to allow me to manage my account without a telephone, I'll have no choice but to close the account. I don't know of another company that will issue me extra cards with whatever name I want on them. If I have to give up my Discover account, I may end up having to pay MetroPCS's ridiculous $3 USD (per transaction, not a one-time fee) for paying in person. If I can find a reloadable gift card, that would work, but I don't think those exist. repeatedly buying nonreloadable gift cards would mean repeatedly buying new cards, each with a few dollar fee for the card itself, as well as having a bunch of used gift cards to fill a landfill with. It doesn't seem like a good option.

I switched to Evolution as my mail client. I have a few complaints, but nothing I can't get over. Evolution has built-in OpenPGP support, so I didn't even need to install anything extra to keep my encryption. The reason I switched away from Claws Mail though is that I can't find a way to synchronize my contacts with a CardDAV server in Claws Mail, with or without plugins. Setting up CardDAV contact synchronization in Evolution was a bit tricky due to the option being labeled as "WebDAV" in Evolution as well as Evolution requiring a trailing slash be added to the URI ownCloud gave me (there wasn't even an error message in Evolution, Evolution simply displayed an empty address book), but most things seem to be in order. I can't figure out how to send encrypted mail to myself, but I don't really need that, I guess, it just makes it easier to test my setup. The other thing I am already missing from Claws Mail is that I can tell Claws Mail to always encrypt, even if I don't have the receiving party's key. If I lack the key, Claws gives me option to send unencrypted or abort. In Evolution, encryption by default doesn't seem to be an option. If I reply to an encrypted message, the encryption check box is checked by default, but otherwise, I need to manually verify that the message will be encrypted. Over all though, I think this will be an upgrade. I really like claws mail, but I miss having access to my address book in my email client. Now that my email address in on a CardDAV server instead of in the client itself, I need an email client that supports that.

Once all that was done, I decided to try to fix my keyboard's space bar, which has not been working properly since before this site began. It simply was not attached correctly; I forget what caused it to become too loose. I managed to pry the space bar off, after which I cleaned underneath it and between some of the other keys a bit. It took quite a while to get the space bar back on properly, and it involved bending some of the metal structure under the space bar but the space bar now functioned properly! The down side? The nub mouse and the mouse buttons quit working. Usually sending the machine to sleep and waking it back up fixes this, but it did not this time. Even after a few reboots, the mouse was not working. I was worried I'd done more damage than good while working with the space bar, but after cleaning around the nub mouse a couple times, everything seems to be working. Maybe when I was cleaning the first time, I moved some of the lodged hairs over too close to the nub mouse and it caused some sort of issue. There was, and still is, a lot of hair in my keyboard.

After dealing with the hardware situation on my laptop, I didn't have time to actually go through my mail like I planned to yesterday. The mouse is locking up much more frequently than before, much of the time as often as every couple minutes, resulting in me having to repeatedly sleep cycle the machine to get the mouse functioning again. Each time I sleep cycle the machine, I have to reenter my password to unlock the screen. Sometimes the mouse has locked up again by the time I can even get the screen unlocked from having been in sleep mode! This is getting very old very fast. Hopefully tomorrow will work out better.

Discover did not write back today. Perhaps it is because Saturday is not a business day, or perhaps it is because they are ignoring me because I don't have a telephone. I'm inclined to believe the former, but the latter is a possibility.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I think this laptop may need to be replaced after all

Day 00064: Sunday, 2015 May 10

My replacement credit union credit card has not yet arrived and Discover is currently keeping me from buying Mark with a C's music. I don't even remember how long the credit union said my card would take for delivery. Was it twelve weeks? That sounds familiar. If it was twelve weeks, I still have a long time to wait. It hasn't even been quite a month yet. If I remembered how long the wait was supposed to be, I would know if it was right to go in in person and ask about the card yet. I didn't keep track of the time frame because I didn't think it would matter. Discover has never locked up my card like this in the past and I usually use my Discover card instead of my credit union card because I like the Discover card management website better.

Cricket has reminded me once again that "my month of service is up" tonight, and asking again that I pay them. I suppose this marks the half-way point to when they will likely finish cutting off my service so I can switch carriers.

The fight to get the text of the Trans-Pacific Partnership made public continues. There is currently a petition by CREDO Mobile to get the president to disclose the details of what this agreement really is. If you care about transparency, please sign it.

CREDO Mobile is in charge of some of the petitions that really should be signed by as many people as possible, but there is a down side to signing them that you should be aware of before doing so. Signing one of their petitions, like signing one of the Daily Kos petitions, signs you up for their mailing list. Unlink the Daily Kos though, CREDO Mobile is trying to sell you CDMA mobile service on a contract. CDMA service is not compatible with free mobile operating systems such as Replicant. The use of service contracts is also a very anti-freedom practice and a very evil business tactic. As activists, they are helping the community, but as a mobile carrier, I would not recommend them. Right now, they want me to buy an iPhone on a two-year contract. If you don't know how I feel both about iPhones and service contracts, you haven't been reading my past weblog entries.

Another petition by CREDO Mobile is an effort to make college education gratis for students. At first, I was kind of reluctant to sign. After all, if the student isn't paying, someone else is. Is it really someone else's responsibility to pay for our education? However, student debt is helping increase the divide between the wealthy and the unwealthy. The wealthy claim they cannot afford to put us through school, but then they turn around and make a killing off our student debt interest. The entire country would be better off if more of its citizens were better educated and we should not be just some tools to increase the wealth of a few. It's time to start closing the divide and create a better world for everyone.

Apparently, there are laws in nineteen states that forbid the government from competing with cable companies to deliver Internet service to citizens. The cable companies try to maximize profits while minimizing costs, so their service is not as fast or as inexpensive as it should be. Municipal broadband is oftem much faster and much more affordable, but as its presence prevents cable companies from having their expensive monopoly, they don't like it. A third CREDO Mobile petition seeks to overturn the absurd laws that allow cable companies to keep their monopoly.

Congress it trying to reauthorize the USA PATRIOT Act through a new act called the USA FREEDOM Act. The final CREDO Mobile petition in my inbox seeks to prevent the USA FREEDOM Act from going through. If the USA FREEDOM Act is passed, currently-illegal NSA spying could not only continue, but actually become legal.

CREDO Mobile has a number of other petitions that warrant attention, but my computer continues to need to be sleep cycled in order for me to even maintain control of the mouse. I now have to sleep cycle the machine a couple times per minute much of the time, up to four times per minute sometimes, and it's been painful enough just to try to get through the petitions that actually get sent to my inbox. I will have to ignore the others for now. It doesn't help that Evolution seems to be much slower than Claws Mail, nor does it handle frequent sleep cycling well. I may need to switch back to Claws Mail soon. Due to these technical difficulties slowing me down substantially, I did not have time to go through the rest of my inbox aside from the CREDO Mobile stuff. Hopefully things will work out better tomorrow, but I wouldn't count on it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My laptop takes it's last breath

Day 00065: Monday, 2015 May 11

Evolution is being a pain about encryption. It refuses to encrypt letters to people unless I have either signed their key to verify that I trust it or I tell Evolution to trust all keys. The fact that I want to encrypt a letter to someone does not necessarily mean that I truly trust that the key belongs to someone in particular. I send letters to people I don't know and do not trust. I still want the NSA to keep out, so I still need these letters encrypted. I've told Evolution to trust all keys for now, but that means I cannot distinguish between keys that I honestly trust and keys that I do not trust. This is suboptimal. I much prefer the way Claws Mail handles it. It warns you that the key is untrusted when you try to send the letter, but allows you to use the key anyway if you like.

I decided to plug in an external mouse to deal with my built-in one locking up continually on me. This solution, while far from ideal, has either comejustin time orhasmadethings worse. The built-in mouse no longer functions at all, even right after waking the machine.

It seems that Cricket finished cutting off my service a full month ahead of when I thought they would. I'm not really prepaired for this. It will be about a month before the SIM cutter arives, and the SIM card for the new plan is too large. This is what I get for counting on a plan that I wasn't paying for any more. It was a gamble from the start, and it did not pay off. Then again though, it did buy me time to find the cheap MetroPCS plan, so in the end, I think it will have worked out for the better.

Maybe tomorrow I will start a three-month experiment, and actually use the MetroPCS tablet. Last time I tried such an experiment, it made me appreciate my Replicant device all the more. While Replicant lacks certain useful features such as wifi connectivity, it more than makes up for it in simple features that Android has no excuse not to have. Android really should have basic ext4 support on SD cards,for one. The internal storage used by the system is formatted as ext4, so the ext4-handling code is all in there, yet for some idiotic reason, Android can't mount an ext4 SD card, claiming the SD card is corrupted or blank. To transfer my music files to the SD card, I need the character set support ext4 has. FAT simply won't cut it. Not to mention that FAT file systems are so easy to break ...

The other option is to go running to T-Mobile proper. I could cancel my plans to attempt to get the MetroPCS $15 USD per month on my Replicant device and just get the T-Mobile $20 USD per month plan. The T-Mobile plan is better in a couple ways anyway. First of all, it doesn't require buying a specific device to get the plan. Second, they plan is entirely SMS-free!

On second though, both of those options are bad ideas. I should at least try to get the MetroPCS plan working, as the SMS feature would keep my mother happy. But at the same time, I can't function well on Android, I've already proven that. The proper choices would be to ether wait the month or so until my SIM cutter arrives or to attempt to cut the SIM card by hand. Either way, the SIM card *must* be cut soon after getting the device. I have seven days from the time that I get the MetroPCS tablet to say "This device does not satisfy me." and get my money back. If the SIM card cannot be cut, fitted into my Replicant device, and the bring working service to it, there is no point in me buying this $150 USD device that I won't even use anyway.

The first of Yst Dawson's two packages arrived today, ahead of schedule.

*(At this point in my writing, my laptop gave out on me and I began writing my weblog entries on my mobile.)*

Day 0:

My computer has just given up the ghost. With both my computer out of commission and my mobile out of service, I now have no connection to the network. I will attempt to keep a personal record of what is going on while I'm disconnected, but without an actual keyboard I may not be as verbose as usual.

As I had been saying before my computer died, my new mobile protective case came in today, ahead of schedule. Unlike my old case the new one seems to be built to be opened and closed repeatedly. For that reason I decided to try it out early because the only reason I have been wanting to wait was to avoid extra damage to the case from opening the case more times than necessary. The new case does seem more durable, but at the same time, it is harder to push the hardware buttons and the main on-screen buttons.

I'm not sure what to do with this. I feel trapped. I need to get ahold of another laptop as soon as possible. Luckily, my most recent backup is from yesterday, so even if I can't recover my hard drive, I shouldn't lose much. I do hope to recover the data from my laptop hard drive though, as it contains the rest of today's web blog entry, which I had been writing when the computer started messing up. At first, the control keys on the laptop quit working. It is when I went to restart the machine in an effort to get the keys to function again, that the computer quit working altogether. It won't even show signs of even starting to boot. The power button simply does nothing. I hope to be back online before my canary expires, but I have no guarantee that this is going to happen. I will probably try to get down to the second-hand computer store on Wednesday, as I have the day off. I would not be able to buy one right away, but I will be able to explain what I need from them and see if they are willing to help.

I tried putting the battery pack in my laptop, and for some reason, the laptop booted once more. I took the opportunity to backup the one file that I did not have backed up from yesterday, which was a partial weblog entry from today. I also updated the copy of my KeePassX database on my mobile as well as copied my PGP key over. It's not like the files will do me any good on mobile though, as I have no network connection. I should have taken the opportunity to update my canary to state that a could be away for an extended period of time and let a few certain people know via email that I'm fine. However, I got cocky and decided to experiment. I shut down my laptop and tried to boot it back up. It would not boot. I had one opportunity to get some last minute things done, and that was all.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The laptop is still dead but at least the mobile is back online

Day 00067: Wednesday, 2015 May 13

Day 2:

First stop of the day, I headed to my credit union to withdraw the cash I would need to buy the MetroPCS tablet. while I was waiting in line, I noticed that I had forgotten to bring my container of SIM cards. I didn't think I would need them for this trip, but I was unhappy to have misplaced them. If successful, I was going to need to pretend that I had forgotten my SIM card at home anyway.

I went down to the T-Mobile store, took the plunge, and asked if the representative would be willing to cut a SIM card from outside T-Mobile. I said I understood that it was a lot to ask and it would be completely fine if she could not do it. She said that she could cut the SIM card, but that she also had to ask why I wasn't on t-mobile. I was prepared though. The settings I had modified yesterday that had caused the reboot loop had been in preparation to show her my mobile and claim that it was in fact on T-Mobile. I claimed that the SIM card I needed cut was for a secondary cheapie device and showed her my old cricket device. The ruse worked, and she questioned me no further. I rummaged around in my bag and pockets, showing that I had forgotten to bring the SIM card with me. Next stop, MetroPCS.

At the MetroPCS store, I asked a couple last minute questions about the tablet, then said I would buy it. A different lady was working there than usual, and it sounded like she was the manager for all the MetroPCS stores in the area. She did not once ask me for my ID and the purchasing seemed to be going off without a hitch. However, when she tried to activate the tablet using her computer, she found that the tablet "had history". It seems that someone had bought that tablet in October and had brought it back for a refund. Due to the nature of the manufacturer's warranty, only the first owner of the tablet after sale is covered. To get around that, MetroPCS returns these slightly-used tablets to the manufacturer instead of selling them to another customer. She had checked inventory before and decided not to bring another tablet into the store because she thought one was already there. Having none that were sellable in inventory, she asked if I would be willing to head to another MetroPCS location to pick up the tablet. She took my money and sent me with the paperwork needed to pick up the tablet elsewhere. Being a pedestrian, I knew it would be a while before I would have the SIM card in hand and make it back to the T-Mobile store to have it cut.

At the second MetroPCS store, I waited in line behind one person, and before finishing helping her, he asked if I was the person coming to pick up the tablet. He did not even look at the paperwork at first, but then said that he probably should because his boss would later see the security camera footage and he did not want to get in trouble for not making sure the tablet went to the right person. I showed him the paperwork and he asked if I wanted help setting up the tablet. I said that I could set it up myself for a few reasons. First, he need not waste his time setting up the tablet fully when I don't plan to use it long. Once the SIM card is activated, there would be no need for me to use the tablet again. Second, I fear that the SIM card would lock itself to the first device it was powered on in. If I could get the SIM card cut and installed in my Replicant device without the SIM card ever entering the tablet, I would stand a better chance of my plan succeeding. Third, I did not want to deal with him potentially trying to talk me into getting a Google account. People assume that if you have an Android, you have a Google account, but that isn't necessarily the case. Much to my surprise, I found the SIM card did not need to be cut at all. it was already the right size to put in my Replicant device. I put the SIM card in, but the Replicant was not able to access the network or SMS features. I tried the SIM card in my old Cricket device as well with the same results. Thinking the SIM card might just not be activated, I tried the SIM card in the new tablet. Unfortunately, it worked perfectly. I don't know if the network is programmed to only accept that SIM card with that tablet serial number or if the network is programmed to only accept that SIM card with that type of tablet, but the fact remains clear. I am NOT able to use the MetroPCS tablet plan on my Replicant.

I headed back to the T-Mobile store to once again make a fool of myself. I explained that while I understood that I would look strange for this, that my plan had changed. I no longer needed a SIM card cut, but I did need a tablet plan for my non-tablet device, the same device that I had previously shown her was already on T-Mobile. She agreed to put me on the prepaid tablet plan, but upon attempting to do so through her computer, she found the option was unavailable. She spoke with one of the other representatives, who said that this was not in fact possible. The only way to get a tablet plan in store was to go postpaid. As a side note, I found out that T-Mobile tablet plans come with unlimited SMS, just like MetroPCS tablet plans.

Instead, I headed to Walmart. Only two non-carrier stores I know of in my area carry SIM cards, and I know for a fact Fred Meyer does not carry T-Mobile SIM cards. They carry AT&T SIM cards, but I would prefer to avoid using the AT&T network. AT&T is opposed to net neutrality and is actively fighting against it. I would rather not fund them. Walmart showed me their T-Mobile tablet plans, but much to my surprise, the $20 plan was not available. Instead, the lowest priced plan was there $30 plan, with 3 gigabytes of data. For the same price, with the same carrier, I can get 5 gigabytes of high speed data, unlimited low speed data, and 100 minutes of talk. So instead grabbed the Straight Talk SIM card, knowing full well that it probably would not work. Straight Talk is a joint effort between Walmart and TracFone. Track phone is an over-controlling reseller, known for locking their SIM cards to the first device that uses them, the practice that I had feared MetroPCS might engage in. I had no reason to believe that they would not also try to lock their tablet plan into only being used on a tablet.

I got the SIM card home and attempted to use the tablet to activate the SIM card on the Web. I was not going to deal with attempts to modify my plan based on my IP address, so I tried to use the Orweb browser to activate the SIM. Unfortunately, the activation website requires the use of JavaScript and Orweb blocks JavaScript. Without root access, there is no good way to get the standard Android browser to use a proxy. I borrowed my brother's laptop, downloaded the Tor browser bundle, and set up the SIM card. quite surprisingly, everything worked fine and my mobile now has a functioning tablet plan.

The Straight Talk starter kit came with four SIM cards, two for AT&T and two for T-Mobile. One for each network was a nano SIM, the other was both a mini and a micro SIM, depending on how you break the card. I chose one of the T-Mobile SIM cards and now have a functioning T-Mobile tablet plan for only $15 per month. The downside is that I only have one gigabyte of data per month, so I will need to attempt to keep my data usage a bit lower than before. I used to go slightly over a gigabyte. Due to having an unlimited data plan, I didn't really need to worry about that.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Marc With a C is awesome!

Day 00073: Tuesday, 2015 May 19

Day 8:

Just before midnight last night, I wrote to Mark With a C about the missing bonus tracks. Just after midnight, just a few minutes later, he wrote back explaining that the bonus tracks from the vinyl record are actually included as part of one of the digital only bonus albums. We then proceeded to chat for a while. I like this guy! He releases his music under the CC BY license because he didn't like finding low bitrate copies of his music on The Pirate Bay. He didn't mind that the music was being pirated, only that it was being pirated as low quality files. So he provided better files under a license that allowed sharing. He switched from a pay-for-all-music sales tactic to a pay-what-you-want-or-don't-pay-at-all sales tactic because one fan was broke but wanted his music. He felt bad for this one person and changed his whole sales scheme. It sounds like he is truly on the same side as his fans.

Of the two bonus albums, one is a live show played by Marc With a C at some point, and the other is an outtake album of songs from a canceled project of his. Every recording of a live show from him that I've heard sounded like it was awesome, and this one was no exception. The outtake album was very different, but to be honest, I didn't get to hear it very well. By the time it was playing, I had moved into a noisy area.

My boss who gave me the idea of trying out laptops by booting them from a Debian USB Drive said at the time that he would bring me one of his USB drives, despite my saying that I would bring one from home for him to install Debian on. He said he had several more than he needed though, so he would just bring one of his. I didn't wait for him though, and yesterday, I setup my own bootable USB Drive. today, he brought me the promised drive, but he said he put a 64 bit system on it and he said I would have to use it to find a 64 bit computer. I explained that many of the 64 bit computers at the recycling center get Windows installed on them by the staff. the computers that don't come with the added price of Windows license are often the 32-bit computers. He said that I could ask them to build me a 64 bit computer, but at that point, I'm either stuck requesting the specifications of the whole computer to make sure it is fully Debian compatible, or I'm potentially stuck with a computer that doesn't have the necessary compatibility with its wireless card and graphics card. I would have to buy it anyway though, as I had them custom build it. In either case, the bootable USB drive does not allow me to test anything until it is too late. I didn't argue, as it would be stupid to argue against someone who was trying to do you a favor, but I am very glad that I managed to set up my own bootable USB drive yesterday.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Carriers of note

Day 00079: Monday, 2015 May 25

Day 14:

I have attempted to contact my coworker about his laptop using the SMS gateway is associated with both his telephone numbers, but have not yet gotten a response.

I looked into a couple of new carriers. The first is Solavei, which offers gratis service if you can get six people to also register for service beneath you. With no one beneath you, the lowest priced plan is 29 dollars. They take 20 dollars off your bill for each three people subscribed beneath you. You can make extra money back, but only if you pay a several hundred dollar one-time fee and hand over your Social Security number. If you can't keep people subscribed under you, even if you were able to get gratis service at one time, your bill will come back. It seems great at first glance, but there is no way to be sure that your bill will stay gratis or even just lower than is available at other places.

The second is Red Pocket Mobile. Red Pocket Mobile offers a ten dollar one gigabyte tablet plan. The catch is that the only way to get the plan seems to be through the Web. Likewise, that is the only way to renew the plan. A credit or debit card is needed. Purchasing a SIM card requires having an account, and creating an account is difficult without my desktop password manager. I could do it using my mobile password manager, but it would be a bit more messy. I would rather wait until I have my new laptop. Besides, I already purchased a second month of service through Straight Talk. Until these two months of service end, it would be a waste of money to switch.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

In-person carrier research

Day 00080: Tuesday, 2015 May 26

Day 15:

Yesterday, when I was looking at the Red Pocket Mobile website, I had gone there looking for the Devote 30 website. I couldn't remember the exact name of the Devote 30 company at first, but I remembered that they sold Red Pocket Mobile plans. I walked into the Devote 30 store today to ask about the availability of tablet plans. The representative said that they do not offer tablet plans. The closest thing that they currently offer is a Verizon 3G mobile hotspot. Verizon 3G service does not use SIM cards, and my device is not Verizon-compatible anyway, so I can't just buy the hotspot for the plan and swap the SIM card into my actual mobile. I mentioned the Red Pocket Mobile $10 tablet plan that is mentioned on the Red Pocket Mobile website. The representative got curious, and looked up the plan himself. He said he would talk to his suppliers, and see if it was possible for him to start offering that plan. He says he will contact me by email when he hears back, but that it could be a while, as the companies don't often get back to him quickly. If this works out, it would mean that I would be able to get the SIM card and possibly even pay for service in person, with no need to expose my credit card details to my new carrier.

While I was in the area, I also checked in with Cricket Wireless and MetroPCS. Cricket Wireless says that they offer service to tablets, but it is the same exact plans as what they offer to smartphones. In other words, you pay for voice services even if your device is not compatible, as you are basically just putting a smartphone plan on a tablet. As much as I think that should be an option, it's the exact opposite of what I'm trying to do. I'm trying to put a tablet plan on a smartphone. MetroPCS says they still do not offer a bring-your-own-tablet option. The only tablet they offer service to is the Pop 7 tablet that they sell.

As some point, I'm going to have to start answering emails again. I was hoping to have a working laptop by now, but I can't just stay out of touch. Several issues arise from dealing with email without my full resources at my disposal, but I will have to make do.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Preparing for the worst

Day 00083: Friday, 2015 May 29

Day 18:

Tomorrow at noon, I will find out from my coworker if he is able to repair my laptop. I decided to spend today preparing for the worst. I shopped around online for Linux laptops. Some websites that supposedly sold Linux laptops didn't seem to have product listing pages or order options. Others were unnavigable by mobile web browser, due to horridly-designed pages that were not very accessible. One site seem to offer the most decent price available, but seemed to be at least two years out of date, judging by the fact that it thought that Debian 6 was still the latest stable version. Another site seemed to offer military-grade durable Linux laptops, but even their lowest-priced option that was not so durable was higher-priced than what was available elsewhere. I settled on three options.

The first option was a laptop from Think Penguin. This machine would have the advantage of modern hardware, out of the box Debian support, and a large penguin logo on the back. While a bit superficial, anyone with any idea what Linux is would not mistake my laptop for being a Windows machine. There also shouldn't be any hardware difficulties. I would upgrade the hard drive to the optional full terabyte hard drive because I need room to expand, and upgrade the amount of RAM to the optional 16 gigabytes. I probably do not need that much RAM, but it would be nice having an ultra-fast machine.

The second option was a laptop from ZaReason. I don't know why, but I somehow get a better vibe from ZaReason than I do from Think Penguin. ZaReason's laptop is higher priced then Think Penguin's. It too has option for upgrading the hard drive to a full terabyte and the RAM to 16 gigabytes. It additionally has the option of upgrading the processor, but I don't know what I'm doing is far as processors. I don't know what upgrading processor will be worth it and it would raise the price even further. Again, modern hardware and out of the box Debian support would be the advantages of this laptop.

The final option is a refurbished machine from Gluglug. I did not look into the pricing of this, but if my past experience with this company is any indication, the laptop would be less expensive than other options, but still very expensive because of a combination of factors. First, a lot of effort is put into the refurbishing process. These machines are not brought back to the original state, instead they are made compatible with a free operating system and the BIOS is completely removed, being replaced with Libreboot and GRUB. The main advantage of this choice is the lack of a proprietary BIOS. However, if Gluglug's new laptop option is anything like their last, there are still replaceable proprietary firmwares in the laptop that the FSF and Gluglug deem too unimportant to be worth replacing. They market it as fully free, but it isn't really. If my system can't be fully free anyway, it might be worth getting newer hardware so I will have less problems. Buying from Gluglug also means buying from the United Kingdom. Last time I bought a machine from Gluglug, the NSA detained the laptop for a period. If I avoid buying from overseas, perhaps the NSA will leave my new laptop alone. Having a free boot stack has been nice in the past though, and without one, it will probably be impossible to completely encrypt the hard drive.

I should wait until tomorrow when I find out about my current laptop before making any real decisions. I do hope my laptop is okay.

I couldn't update my canary today, as I was cut off from my Web/ssh server.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I finally return home

Day 00084: Saturday, 2015 May 30

At long last, Yst Dawson is back!

Let me start at the beginning. I was not and am not being held against my will. I was not and am not being kept away from the Internet by force or threat of force. Rather, I have been kept away from my home, Yst Domain, by mere technical difficulty. Three Mondays ago, my Lenovo ThinkPad X60s, my only terminal for updating this site and the contained canary, died on me. A little later that same day, my Samsung GT-I9300's mobile connection also expired, a full month ahead of when I expected it to. With these tho machines out of commission, I was entirely cut off from the Internet. I managed to register for a new mobile plan using my brother's laptop, which put me back on the Internet, albeit though a tiny difficult-to-use portal. However, this didn't give me access to my home of Yst Domain, and I was unable to reach my canary to feed it. Unfortunately, my canary died on me.

I spent that time looking for a way to get a full laptop again, so I could return home. I looked into second-hand machines, but the ones I could find all had issues. Some were Apple products, which would be unlikely to provide a decent host for my Debian environment. Some were Windows machines, which would mean that I would be paying Microsoft for a Windows license, despite the fact that I would be wiping the Windows system from the machine as soon as possible. I wouldn't mind the extra cost if that money went to the recycling center, but I don't want my money going to pay for proprietary software if I can help it. The final laptop I saw ran Zorin OS and only cost $99 USD. However, this laptop's Wi-Fi card proved to be incompatible with Debian, due likely to needing proprietary firmware that Debian lacks. I can't plug directly into the home router most of the time due to its location, so working Wi-Fi is not negotiable.

At one point, I mentioned my laptop dying to one of my coworkers, who I didn't know was a computer guy. He doesn't do software, but he says he knows his hardware. He offered to take a look at my laptop and to try to diagnose it. He took the laptop two days ago, and said he would bring it back at noon today. Thus ends the abridged summery of the current hole in my weblog.

Today, he brought the laptop back with a diagnosis, as promised. He said that the issue was that the battery was dead. I explained that the battery had been dead for a while and that for that reason, I've been only using it when connected directly to a wall outlet. He said that if that wasn't the issue, the issue was the power button. According to him, if the power button was functioning but something else in the computer was preventing a proper boot, the computer would stir to life when the power button was pressed, even if only for a moment before shutting back down. He said that if I could procure a new power button, which would only cost around $5 USD, either he or I could install it and the machine should come back to life. If I could bring him even an incorrect power button, he said he could jury-rig it and fix the machine. It wouldn't be pretty, but it would work.

I didn't know where to get a laptop power button, and the local computer shops did not have one available. I tried online, but the only power buttons that turned up in search results were for the Lenovo ThinkPad X60 tablet, not the Lenovo ThinkPad X60s laptop. I would have even tried ordering one that said it was compatible with the Lenovo ThinkPad *X60* laptop, as I know the X60 and X60s have some interchangeable parts, but tablet parts don't seem like they would work in a laptop. Next, I went to the recycling center. They carry broken laptops that are sold for parts, in addition to their stock of working computers. I hoped to find one with a power button that was about the right size. Much to my delight, I found four such buttons on machines, one on a Lenovo ThinkPad T30 laptop and three on Lenovo ThinkPad X60 tablets. It seems that these X60 tablets are not the same thing as what we think of as tablets today. Rather, they are just laptops in which the screen can be reversed and the keyboard folded up behind the monitor. One of the tablets had its keyboard hanging loose, and I saw that the power button is actually a part of the keyboard. With this new knowledge, I thought replacing the whole keyboard shouldn't be too difficult, and chose the cheapest of the three tablets for $25 USD. The T30 had the right size of power button, but not the right size of keyboard, so I ruled it out.

Once home, I dismantled what was left of the tablet, recovering the keyboard and two sticks of RAM. Components such as the hard drive were missing. To be honest, I'm surprised that the recycling center didn't take the RAM to sell separately. I took the keyboard off my own X60s, but I found that the keyboard came off too easily. The electronic strip that passes signals from the keyboard to the motherboard was not connected. Curiously, I connected the laptop's own keyboard and tried to power on the machine. Keyboard hanging out, the X60s stirred, bringing up the familiar GRUB error message about the system not being found (due to the full disk encryption). It lives!

The recycling center doesn't take back broken laptops that are sold for parts, but I think the lesson I learned was worth the $25 USD. I'll keep the X60 tablet around in case the parts become relevant at a later date. I had everything I needed to fix the X60s all along, save for the knowledge. The mouse is built into the keyboard as well, so there is a strong possibility that fixing the connection has fixed my malfunctioning mouse as well. As of yet, I have not had it give out on me. It's also highly-probable that I disrupted the connection myself when I was attempting to clean out the keyboard of hair and other debris or when I was fixing the space bar.

At this point, I think my to do list is clear:

0: Process email
1: Format and upload my offline logs of my time stuck away from home
2: Work on my PHP syntax highlighting function so I can repair and upload March 21's weblog entry

I think processing about a month's worth of email takes priority over formatting and uploading the low-level details of my time away, so that will have to wait.

Copyright © 2015 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.